Finding Aid for the Zunz
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Zunz Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0000a
.01 linear_feet
- I. Manuscripts
  - (manuscript, pp. 2) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 1)
  - Louis Rosenzweig (manuscript, p. 10) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 2)
  - Louis Rosenzweig (manuscript, pp. 1) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 3)
  - Zunz - “Vorwort” (manuscript and typescript, pp. 10) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 4)
  - Zunz - “Briefe” (typescript and manuscript, pp. 11) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 5)
  - “L. Zunz zum Gedächtnis” I. Elbogen (NNG notes?) (manuscript, pp. 10) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 6)
  - “Über den Begriff einer Wissenschaft des Judentums.” Immanuel Wolf, for publication in Zeitschrift für die Wissenschaft des Judentums 1,1(1822) (typescript, pp. 17) (copy) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 7)
  - “Die Wissenschaft des Judentums: Ihre methoden und geistesgeschichtlichen Probleme”Dr. Heinz Moshe Grabe (typescript, photostat, pp. 4) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 8)
- II. Correspondence
  - Between the Zunz/Ehrenberg Families
    - Letters (1866-79) (manuscript) (16) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters (1845-46) (manuscript) (18) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters (1872-74) (manuscript) (16) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters (1875-85) (manuscript) (11) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters (1850-51) (manuscript) (6) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters (1853-55) (manuscript) (9) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 14)
    - Letters (1869-71) (manuscript) (6) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters (1946-48) (manuscript) (23) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters (1854-71) (manuscript) (Phillipp Ehrenberg, Julie Ehrenberg, Leopold and Adelheid Zunz) (23) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters (1845-54) (manuscript) (Julie Fischel, Julie Ehrenberg, Phillipp Ehrenberg, Leopold and Adelheid Zunz) (17) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters (1833-1879) (manuscript) and 1 envelope (6) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 19)
    - Letter by Adelheid Zunz (?) (manuscript) Original and photostat) (2) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 20)
    - Letters (Adelheid Zunz, Henriette Moeyer (?), Victor, and Dr. Ehrenberg) (manuscript) (7) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 21)
    - Letters (Rosa Zunz, Julie and Phillipp Ehrenberg) (manuscript and typescript) (7) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters: Adelheid Zunz (typescript, copies) (9) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 23)
    - Letters (Phillipp Ehrenberg, Moritz Lazarus, and M. Kirschstein (typescript, copies) (18) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 24)
    - Letters to M. Isler and S.M. Ehrenberg (1824, 1838) (copied by NNG?) (manuscript) (3) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 25)
    - Letter - Leopold and Adelheid Zunz to Phillipp Ehrenberg, (6.15.1833?) (typescript, pp. 3, copy?) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 26)
    - Letter - Leopold and Adelheid Zunz to Phillipp Ehrenberg, (5.23.1833?) (typescript, pp. 6, copy) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 27)
    - Letter - Leopold and Adelheid Zunz to Phillipp Ehrenberg (12.6.1833) (typescript, pp. 5, copy) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 28)
    - Letters - S.M. Ehrenberg and M.I. Jost (?), (1852) (manuscript) and 1 NNG note (5) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Letters to Adele (Alice) Rosenzweig from Jacob Lestschinsky (1.8.1932, 1.13.1932, 3.14.1932 and 4.4.1932) (typescript) (4) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 30)
    - Letters to NNG (typescript and manuscript) (15) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 31)
    - Letters to NNG (manuscript, typescript and photostat) (17) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 32)
    - Letter to Jacob R. Marcus from NNG (typescript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 33)
    - Letter to Dan from Pa (NNG?) (2.5.1961) (manuscript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 34)
    - Letter, “Dear Friend” from “Z” (Zunz?) (1.8.1853) (XIV-2-) (typescript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 35)
    - Letter to Adolf Oko from Elbogen (?) (8.30.1926) (manuscript, photostat) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 36)
    - Letter to Dr. Ismar Elbogen from Adolf Oko, (10.19.1926) (typescript, photostat) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 37)
    - Letter to ? from “Z” (Zunz?) (12.5.1819?) (original and copy?) (2) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 38)
    - Letter (Hebrew) Yeshiva University (manuscript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 39)
    - Letters from? to Rosa Zunz, (8.11.1850 and 12.21.1874) (typescript, photostats) (2) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 40)
    - Letter to ? from Prof. Dr. M. Brann (8.9.1917?) (typescript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 41)
- III. Notes
  - (NNG and ?) (manuscript) (10) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 42)
  - (NNG and ?) (manuscript) (15) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 43)
  - (NNG) (manuscript) (11) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 44)
  - (NNG) (manuscript) (15) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 45)
  - (NNG and ?) (manuscript) (24) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 46)
  - (NNG and ?) (manuscript) (8) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 47)
  - (NNG) (manuscript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 48)
  - (NNG, Adelheid Zunz, Julie Ehrenberg and ?) (manuscript) (5) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 49)
  - (NNG) (manuscript) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 50)
- IV. Page Notations
  - Manuscript (NNG) (12pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 51)
  - Manuscript (NNG) (16pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 52)
  - Manuscript (NNG) (12pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 53)
  - Manuscript (NNG) (14pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 54)
  - Manuscript (NNG) (11pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 55)
  - Manuscript (NNG) (11pp) (Box Zunz 1, Folder 56)
- V. Offprints
  - Feier der Silberne Hochzeit Herrn Samuel Meyer Ehrenberg und Frau Inspectorin Henriette Ehrenberg, (10.13.1833) (2) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 57)
  - Feier der Silberne Hochzeit Herrn Samuel Meyer Ehrenberg und Frau Inspectorin Henriette Ehrenberg, (10.13.1833) (copy 2) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 58)
  - Feier der Silberne Hochzeit Herrn Samuel Meyer Ehrenberg und Frau Inspectorin Henriette Ehrenberg, (10.13.1833) (copy 3) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 59)
  - “Dem Herrn Königwerder an Seinem Hockzeitstagemit der Demoiselle Friederike Samson”, S.M.Ehrenberg (1817) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 60)
  - “Rede am Grabe des Herrn S.M. Ehrenberg” by Cohn (1854) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 61)
  - “Plan zur Unterstutzungs - Anstalt für Wittwen und Waisen verstorbener Mitglieder der Gesellschaft der Freunde” (1811) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 62)
  - “Einige brüderliche Worte gewidmet meinem gebliebten Bruder S. M. Ehrenberg ... am Tage der Feier seiner Silbermen Hochzeit” (1833) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 63)
  - “Stauten der Gesellschaft der Freunde” (1817) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 64)
- VI. Miscellaneous
  - Certificate (?) May 1847 (Box Zunz 2, Folder 65)
  - Assorted items (offprints and photostats) (8) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 66)
  - Hebrew notations (manuscript, typescript and xerox, pp. 8) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 67)
  - Time Lines of 19th Century (NNG) (manuscript, pp. 16) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 68)
  - Biographies of Leopold Zunz? (2) and Family trees (2) (NNG) (manuscript and typescript, pp. 21) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 69)
  - Information sheets of Zunz's letters? (1822-1844) (NNG) (manuscript, pp. 8) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 70)
  - Information sheets of Zunz's letters? (1845-1849) (NNG) (manuscript, pp. 9) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 71)
  - Information sheets of Zunz's letters? (1850-1873) (NNG) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 72)
  - Diplom des “Verein für Cultur und Wissenschaft der Juden” (1822) (Diploma?) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 73)
  - Envelope addressed to Otto Ehrenberg from W. Ehrenberg (manuscript) (Box Zunz 2, Folder 74)